Guide to the Chanticleer Photograph Collection, 1998-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Chanticleer Photograph collection 1998-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Undergraduate Publications Board.
29.0 linear feet Extent: 22,500 items Items
The Chanticleer is Duke's annual student-produced yearbook. Focus is placed on high- quality photographs. The collection includes photographs, slides, negatives and contact sheets. Duplicates exist throughout the collection. The Collection also includes editing notes from Chanticleer staff. Most of the photographs are in black and white, although there are some in color. They range in date from circa 1998-ongoing.
RL.01452
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Chanticleer Photograph Collection were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 2002-2003 and 2012.
Historical Note
The Chanticleer is Duke's annual student-produced yearbook. The first issue was published in 1912. Its production is managed by the Undergraduate Publications Board.
Collection Overview
The Chanticleer Photograph Collection includes photographs, slides, negatives and contact sheets. Duplicates exist throughout the collection. The collection also includes editing notes from Chanticleer staff. Most of the photographs are in black and white, although there are some in color, and the majority of them are unidentified. They range in date from circa 1998-ongoing.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- Athletics.; Duke University -- Basketball.; Duke University -- Buildings.; Duke University. Chapel.; Duke University -- Faculty.; Duke University -- Football.; Duke University -- History -- 20th Century.; Duke University. Hoof’n’Horn.; Duke University -- Lacrosse.; Duke University. Marine Laboratory.; Duke University -- Student housing.; Duke University -- Students.
Related Material
The Chanticleer Yearbook
University Archives. Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, circa 1998-2003, 13 Boxes
  - 8x10 Photographs (approx. 189) (Box 1)
    Subjects: Volleyball, Women’s Basketball, Men’s Basketball, Women’s Soccer, Men’s Soccer, Women’s Tennis, Men’s Tennis, Women’s Lacrosse, Men’s Lacrosse, Swimming, Baseball, Field Hockey, Dancers, Football, Cheerleaders, Women’s Golf and MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - 5x7 Photographs (approx. 6)
    Subjects: Student groups, miscellaneous.
  - 4x6 Photographs (approx. 806)
    Subjects: Football, Volleyball, Men’s Basketball, Baseball, Men’s Soccer, Women’s Soccer, Men’s Tennis, Women’s Tennis, Women’s Lacrosse, People and Group Shots, Fraternity Road Trip and Social, Carl Berstein, ESPN at Cameron Indoor Stadium, Student Activities, Chevy Chase, Campus Buildings, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - Slides - Subjects: Football
  - Contact Sheets - Various shots
  - Negatives -- Subjects: Sports, campus buildings, students
  - 8x10 Photographs (approx. 358) (Box 2)
    Subjects: Stomp! Broadway at Duke, Landscapes/Artsy, Campus Exteriors and Interiors, Lauren MacWilliams, Fraternities, Azim Barodawala, Shared Living Groups, People, Grateful Dead, Football, Men’s Basketball, Women’s Lacrosse, MLK Day, Student Activities/Life, Laila El-Haddad, George Gopen, Women’s Soccer, Men’s Soccer, David Johnson, Jaiko Moveno, DUI Seniors, Sororities, Hoof-n-Horn, Duke EMS, Jeremy Huff, Volleyball, Women’s Tennis, Field Hockey, Rusty Shappley, Swimming Coach, Women’s Golf, Men’s Golf, Track and Field, Janet DickensonEnter scope/content note.
  - 5x7 Photographs (approx. 42)
    Subjects: Landscape/Artsy, Stomp! Broadway at Duke, Kevin Nealon, Campus Exteriors, Student Activities/Life, Men’s Lacrosse, Women’s Lacrosse, Women’s Tennis, Women’s SoccerEnter scope/content note.
  - 4x6 Photographs (approx. 150)
    Subjects: Campus Exteriors, Student Activities/Life, Cheerleaders, Men’s Basketball, FootballEnter scope/content note.
  - Slides
    Subjects: Dr. Drew, Student Life, Lauren MacWilliams, People, Campus Exteriors, BonfireEnter scope/content note.
  - Contact Sheets
    Subjects: Grateful Dead, Student Activities/Life, Men’s Basketball, Men’s Tennis, Women’s Lacrosse, Women’s Basketball, Campus Exteriors and Interiors, Laila El-Haddad, George Gopen, David Johnson, Jaiko Moveno, DUI Seniors, Hoof-n-Horn, Duke EMS, Azim Barodawala, People, Rusty Shappley, Graduation 2000, Wrestling, Track and FieldEnter scope/content note.
  - Negatives
    Subjects: Men’s Basketball, Men’s Tennis,Women’s Lacrosse, Student Activities/Life, Campus Exteriors and Interiors, Women’s Basketball, Laila El-Haddad, George Gopen, David Johnson, Jaiko Moveno, DUI Seniors, Hoof-n-Horn, Duke EMS, Azim Barodawala, Rusty ShappleyEnter scope/content note.
  - 8x10 Photographs (approx. 245) (Box 3)
    Subjects: People, Student Activities/Life, Men’s Basketball, Baseball, Wrestling, Fencing, Men’s Lacrosse, Men’s Tennis, Men’s Soccer, Monty Reichert, Jenny Lee, Native American Dances, Vagina Monologues, Hockey, Campus Exteriors, Carl Berstein, Richard Hatch, Chevy Chase, Tom Selleck, K. S. Lee, Jordan Barynsky, Upright Citizen’s BrigadeEnter scope/content note.
  - 8x12 Photographs (approx. 7)
    Subjects: Rowing/Crew in color Enter scope/content note.
  - 5x7 Photographs (approx. 6)
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, PeopleEnter scope/content note.
  - 4x6 Photographs (approx. 621)
    Subjects: Upright Citizen’s Brigade, Student Activities/Life, Richard Hatch, Campus Exteriors, Spike Lee, Men’s Basketball, Men’s Soccer, Women’s Soccer, Field Hockey, Volleyball, Wildlife, Maya Angelou Enter scope/content note.
  - Slides
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Campus Exteriors, People
  - Contact Sheets
    Subjects: Monty Reichert, Jordan Barynsky, Jim Lazarus, Hada Yousef, Carliss Chatman, Rob Leonard, E. Sanders, Pooja Kumar, Elizabeth Fischer, Mike GustafsonEnter scope/content note.
  - Negatives
    Subjects: K. S. Lee, Jordan Barynsky, Jim Lazarus, Upright Citizen’s Brigade, Richard Hatch, Campus Exteriors, Baseball, Women’s Soccer, Field Hockey, VolleyballEnter scope/content note.
  - 8x10 Photographs (approx. 272) (Box 4)
    Subjects: Shared Living Groups, Fraternities, Sororities, People, Football, Women and Men’s Cross Country, Women’s Soccer, Student Activities/Life, Duke EMS, Volleyball, Field Hockey, Men’s Soccer, Steve Nowicki, Al Franken, Women’s Basketball, Men’s Basketball, Coach K, Lisa Ling, Fencing, Women’s Lacrosse, Wrestling, Elizabeth Dole, Johnnie Cochran, Dr. Drew, Professor Montague, Joe Pietrantoni, Cheerleaders, Campus Exteriors, Track and Field, Dancers, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - 5x7 Photographs (approx. 14)
    Subjects: Sororities, Fraternities, copies of pictures from the Duke University Archives, Chapel (color)Enter scope/content note.
  - 4x6 Photographs (1) -- Subject: Student Activities/Life
  - Slides -- Subjects: Student Life, Bonfire, Duke Gardens
  - Negatives -- Subject: Men’s Basketball
  - 4x6 Photographs (approx. 1,346) (Box 5)
    Subjects: Men’s Soccer, Women’s Soccer, Football, Field Hockey, Volleyball, Student Activities/Life, Johnnie Cochran, People, Leslie Nielson, Jocelyn Elders, Men’s Basketball, Al Franken, Campus Exteriors and Interiors, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - Slides (19 cases)
    Subjects: Men’s Basketball, Student Activities/Life, Volleyball, FootballEnter scope/content note.
  - Contact Sheets -- Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Sports
  - Negatives
    Subjects: Men and Women’s Soccer, Football, Volleyball, Field Hockey, Student Activities/Life, Johnnie Cochran, Campus Exteriors and InteriorsEnter scope/content note.
  - 8x10 Photographs (approx. 5) (Box 6)
    Subject: Student Activities/Life
  - 4x6 Photographs (approx. 329)
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Leslie Nielson, Wrestling, Men’s Basketball, Track and Field, Wilson Gym, Campus Exteriors, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - Slides
    Subjects: Duke Gardens, Student Activities/Life, Men’s Basketball, SpeakersEnter scope/content note.
  - Negatives -- Subjects: Men’s Basketball, Campus Exteriors, Sports
  - 8x10 Photographs (approx. 237) (Box 7)
    Subjects: Sororities, Fraternities, Shared Living Groups, Marine Lab, Student Activities/Life, Greg Louganis, Men and Women’s Soccer, Volleyball, Men and Women’s Basketball, Women and Men’s Tennis, Track and Field, Women and Men’s Lacrosse, People/Speakers, Carrot Top, Jane Goodall, Maya Angelou, Football, Field Hockey, Fencing, Baseball, Cheerleaders, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - 5x7 Photographs (approx. 12)
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Bill Bradley, Swimming, Wrestling, Women and Men’s GolfEnter scope/content note.
  - 4x6 Photographs (approx. 1,051)
    Subjects: Women and Men’s Basketball, Women and Men’s Lacrosse, Baseball, Student Activities/LifeEnter scope/content note.
  - Contact Sheets
    Subjects: Women and Men’s Basketball, Women and Men’s Lacrosse, Baseball, Student Activities/Life, Wrestling, Men and Women’s Tennis, Rowing, Football, Volleyball, Fencing, Track and Field, Field Hockey, Diving, Swimming, People/SpeakersEnter scope/content note.
  - 4x6 Photographs (approx. 1,021) (Box 8)
    Subjects: Octoberfest, Men’s Basketball, Football, Campus Life, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - Slides (49 Cases)
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Campus Life, Campus Exteriors, Men’s Basketball, Women’s Soccer, Track and Field, Football, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - Negatives -- Subjects: Octoberfest, Football, Men’s Basketball
  - 8x10 Photographs (approx. 323) (Box 9)
    Subjects: Students, Sororities, Fraternities, Student Activities/Life, Men’s Soccer, Men’s Lacrosse, Men and Women’s Tennis, Wrestling, Spike Lee, Upright Citizen’s Brigade, Volleyball, Field Hockey, Track and Field, Myrlie Evers and John Hope Franklin, Rowing, Men’s Basketball, Tom Selleck, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - 5x7 Photographs (approx. 19)
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Kokie Roberts, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - 4x6 Photographs (approx. 32)
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Men’s Basketball, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - Slides
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Campus Exteriors, Men’s Basketball, Men’s Soccer, Wyclef Jean, Lisa Ling, Maya Angelou, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - Contact Sheets -- Subjects: Student Activities/Life
  - Negatives -- Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Miscellaneous
  - 4x6 Photographs (approx. 2,184) (Box 10)
  - Negatives
    Subjects: Football, Dorm Pictures, Men’s Soccer, Men and Women’s Basketball, Bonfire, Volleyball, Student Life, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - Slides -- Subjects: Wyclef Jean, K-ville, Student Activities/Life, Bonfires (Box 11)
  - 8x10 Photographs (approx. 192) (Box 12)
    Subjects: Students, Campus Exteriors, Volleyball, Football, Men and Women’s Soccer, Men and Women’s Basketball, Field Hockey, Track and Field, Women’s Lacrosse, Women’s Tennis, Swimming, Baseball, Wrestling, Cross Country, Penn and Teller, Bonfire, Fencing, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - 5x7 Photographs (approx. 110)
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, People, Men’s Lacrosse, Men’s Golf, Volleyball, Wrestling, MiscellaneousEnter scope/content note.
  - 4x6 Photographs (approx. 13) -- Subject: Student Activities/Life
  - Slides
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Campus Exteriors, Michael Moore, Men and Women’s Soccer, Women’s Tennis, Men and Women’s Basketball, Dorm Groups, Julian Bond, Track and Field, Bonfire, K-ville, Volleyball, Swimming, FencingEnter scope/content note.
  - Contact Sheets
  - Negatives
    Subjects: Student Activities/Life, Campus Exteriors, Michael Moore, Men and Women’s Soccer, Women’s Tennis, Men and Women’s Basketball, Dorm Groups, Julian Bond, Track and Field, Bonfire, K-ville, Volleyball, Swimming, Fencing
  - A2002-75 (Oversize 13)
    Miscellaneous Girl, Elvis Costello?, Rugby, Men’s Lacrosse with name Tim Buzby. These are all matted. Also includes 2 contact sheets and one 8x10 miscellaneous person photo that are stuck together.
  - A2003-1
    Kappa Kappa Gamma 1999 and Alpha Omicron Pi 1999
  - UA2012-0001 (Box 14)
    Subjects include: campus life, jugglers, ROTC, athletics/sports, student life, music, events, academics, speakers, tap dancing, dorm life
  - UA2012-0001 (Box 15)
    Subjects include: campus life, athletics/sports, dorm life, student life, graduation, speakers, performances
  - UA2012-0001 (Box 16)
    Subjects include: campus life, athletics/sports, performances
  - UA2012-0001 (Box 17)
    Subjects include: campus life, campus scenes, athletics/sports, dorm life
  - UA2012-0001 (Box 18)
    Subjects include: campus life, student life, athletics/sports, performances, speakers
  - UA2012-0001 (Box 19-21)
    Layout Sheets